Emmy Lou Packard
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Emmy Lou Packard papers
1900-1990
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Packard, Emmy Lou
9.4 linear feet
The Emmy Lou Packard papers measure 9.4 linear feet and date from 1900 to 1990, and focus on the career of painter, printmaker, muralist, and sculptor Emmy Lou Packard. Also found are extensive materials relating to Packard's personal and professional relationship with muralist Diego Rivera and painter Frida Kahlo, with whom Packard lived for one year in Mexico. Papers include correspondence, financial records, notes, writings, exhibition files, photographs, and printed material.
Biographical Note
Emmy Lou Packard was born in Imperial Valley, California on April 15, 1914, to Walter and Emma Leonard Packard. In the late 1920s she lived with her family in Mexico City where she became acquainted with Diego Rivera, from whom she received regular art criticism and encouragement. She graduated from University of California, Berkeley and completed courses in fresco and sculpture at the California School of Fine Arts in 1940. That year and the next, Packard worked as a full-time painting assistant to Rivera on his 1,650 square-foot fresco at the World's Fair in San Francisco. During this project, Packard became very close to Rivera and Frida Kahlo and returned to Mexico with them and spent a year living with the couple.
From then on, except for a year spent in 1943 working for a defense plant, Packard worked and grew in various aspects of her art. In addition to her work in fresco, Packard is known for her work in watercolor, oil, mosaic, laminated plastic, concrete and printmaking, both in linocuts and woodblocks. She went to Europe, received numerous commissions that included installations for ships, hotels, and private homes for which she executed large woodcuts and mural panels. During the 1950s and 1960s, Packard was hired to restore several historic murals, most notably the Rincon Annex Post Office mural by Anton Refregier and the Coit Tower murals in San Francisco.
Between 1966 and 1967 commissioned by architects, she designed and executed a number of concrete and mosaic pieces, one of which went to the Mirabeau Restaurant in Kaiser Center, Oakland. She also designed and executed a mural for the Fresno Convention Center Theater in that same period. In 1973-1974, she designed and supervised a glazed brick mural for a public library in Pinole, California.
Packard had one-woman shows at the San Francisco Museum of Art, the Raymond and Raymond Gallery (San Francisco), the Addison Gallery of American Art (Andover, Mass.), Connecticut Academy of Fine Arts, the Pushkin Museum (Moscow), and the March Gallery in Chicago. Emmy Lou Packard died in 1998.
Scope and Content Note
The Emmy Lou Packard papers measure 9.4 linear feet and date from 1900 to 1990, and focus on the career of painter, printmaker, muralist, and sculptor Emmy Lou Packard. Also found are extensive materials relating to Packard's personal and professional relationship with muralist Diego Rivera and painter Frida Kahlo, with whom Packard lived for one year in Mexico. Papers include correspondence, financial records, notes, writings, exhibition files, photographs, and printed material.
Biographical materials include resumes and personal fomrs and certificates. Correspondence is with family, friends, and colleagues, including muralist Anton Refregier, songwriter Malvina Reynolds, and composer John Edmunds. There is one letter from Dorothea Lange. Also found is correspondence with various political and arts organizations, such as the American Civil Liberties Union and the Russian magazine Soviet Woman. Much of the correspondence discusses personal relationships and political and art-related activities. Additional correspondence with and concerning Diego Rivera and Frida Kahlo is arranged in Series 6.
Personal business records found within the papers include real estate and rent records, insurance records, price lists for art work, consignment records, and miscellaneous receipts. There is one interview transcript of an interview with Packard for the Radical Elders Oral History Project. The papers include a series of notebooks/diaries, address lists, and other notes, as well as typescripts and additional writings by Packard and others. Exhibition and project files for many of Packard's commissioned projects are also found within the collection, including her files for the restoration of Anton Refregier's Rincon Annex Post Office mural in San Francisco and the Coit Tower murals in San Francisco. Many of the project files contain correspondence, reports, contracts, printed material, photographs, and art work. Additional art work consists of orginal drawings and prints by Packard and others not directly associated with projects.
The papers also include photographs of Packard, her family, residences, artwork, friends, and colleagues, including Cesar Chavez, Juan O'Gorman, Malvina Reynolds, Charles Safford, Ralph Stackpole, and Tennessee Williams. Two scrapbooks are found as well as additional printed materials such as clippings and exhibition announcements and catalogs.
Packard's reference files and personal documents documenting her professional and close personal relationship with Diego Rivera and Frida Kahlo are arranged into a separate series and include her research files for a planned, but unpublished, book on the two artists, personal letters between Packard and the couple, as well as several interesting photographs. Also found in this series are notes, writings, and printed materials relating to Diego Rivera, Frida Kahlo, and other Mexican artists, such as Covarrubius, Juan O'Gorman, and Pablo O'Higgins.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into fifteen series.
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1942-1985 (Box 1; 1 folder; Reel 5812)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1919-1990, undated (Boxes 1-3; 2.6 linear feet; Reels 5812-5814)
Series 3: Personal Business Records, 1945-1985, undated (Box 3; 21 folders; Reel 5814)
Series 4: Interview Transcript, 1979 (Box 3; 1 folder; Reel 5814)
Series 5: Notes, 1900-1985, undated (Boxes 3-4; 1.1 linear feet; Reels 5814-5816)
Series 6: Reference Files on Diego Rivera and Frida Kahlo, 1929-1986 (Box 5, 10, OV 11; 0.9 linear feet; Reels 5816-5817)
Series 7: Writings by Packard, 1953-1984 (Box 5; 17 folders; Reel 5817)
Series 8: Writings by Others, 1955-1984, undated(Boxes 5-6; 19 folders; Reel 5817)
Series 9: Art Work, 1921-1976 (Box 6, OV 11; 10 folders; Reel 5817)
Series 10: Exhibition Files, 1950-1964 (Box 6, OV 11; 5 folders; Reel 5816)
Series 11: Project Files, 1953-1985 (Boxes 6-7, 10, OV 11; 1.8 linear feet; Reels 5817-5818)
Series 12: Photographs, 1914-1982 (Box 8, 10; 0.8 linear feet; Reel 5819)
Series 13: Scrapbooks, 1947-1950, undated(Box 10; 0.2 linear feet; Reel 5819)
Series 14: Printed Material, 1936-1988, undated (Boxes 8-9, 10; 1 linear foot; 5819-5820)
Series 15: Artifacts, 1984, undated (Box 9, 10; 2 folders; unfilmed)
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
O'Gorman, Juan, 1905-; Kahlo, Frida; Lange, Dorothea; Rivera, Diego, 1886-1957; Covarrubias, Miguel, 1904-1957; O'Higgins, Pablo, 1904-; Public Works of Art Project
Subjects-Topical:
Mural painting and decoration, Mexican; Mural painting and decoration, American; Sculptors -- California -- San Francisco; Muralists -- California -- San Francisco; Painters -- California -- San Francisco; Printmakers -- California -- San Francisco
Types of Materials:
Photographs; Works of art; Scrapbooks; Sketches; Diaries; Interviews
Names:
Reynolds, Malvina; O'Gorman, Juan, 1905-; Edmunds, John, 1913-; Rivera, Diego, 1886-1957; Kahlo, Frida; Refregier, Anton, 1905-; American Civil Liberties Union
Provenance
Emmy Lou Packard donated her papers to the Archives of American Art from 1985-1988.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Patrons must use microfilm copy.
Alternative Forms Available
The microfilm is available on microfilm reels 5812-5820 and for interlibrary loan.
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Material, 1942-1985, Series 1:; (Box 1; 1 folder)
  One file containing resumes, a 1942 report card, an application form, a driver's license, and a 1973 prenuptial agreement with Louis Jackson Owen
  - Biographical Material, 1942-1985 (Box 1, Reel 5812)
- Correspondence, 1919-1990, undated, Series 2:; (Boxes 1-3; 2.6 linear feet)
  Chronologically arranged correspondence files primarily with family and colleagues discussing personal relationships and political and art-related activities in the San Francisco area. Correspondents include Anton Refregier, songwriter Malvina Reynolds, and composer John Edmunds. Packard also corresponded with various organizations such as the American Civil Liberties Union, and publishers of the Russian magazine Soviet Woman. There is also one letter from Dorothea Lange. Undated letters are arranged alphabetically according to the correspondents' surnames.
  See Appendix A for an alphabetized list of notable correspondents. See Also Series 6, Reference Files on Diego Rivera and Frida Kahlo for additional correspondence.
  See index for Notable Correspondents from Series 2: Correspondence
  Index: Notable Correspondents from Series 2: Correspondence
  Aberdeen (Washington) Public Library, 1985 (1 letter)
  Abraham Lincoln Brigade, 1985 (1 letter)
  Achenbach Foundation for Graphic Artster Troche, 1965 (1 letter)
  Acker, Sylvia, 1967 (1 letter)
  ACLU Foundation of Northern California, 1985
  Addison Gallery of American Art, 1948-1968 (3 letters)
  Affiliated Art Groups (AAG), 1955 (3 letters)
  Agins, Minna, 1974-1980 (6 letters)
  Alexander-Willis, Hope, 1980-1985 (3 letters)
  Allen, Wheat and Rosemary, [1961] (1 letter)
  American Broadcasting Companies, Inc., 1976 (1 letter)
  American Civil Liberties Union, 1965 (5 letters)
  American Russian Institute: 1958-1985 (25 letters, including letters from Holland Roberts)
  Ames, William, 1968-1974 (3 letters)
  Anglim, Paule M. (Architectural Art Services), 1964-1966 (5 letters): see also Diamond Heights Redevelopment Area Decorative Wall project
  Aptheker, Herbert (American Institute of Marxist Studies), 1977 (1 letter): see also California State College, Sonoma
  Archives for the Performing Arts, 1984 (1 letter)
  Archives of American Art, 1965-1990 (4 letters)
  Arriba Juntos, 1985 (1 letter): re Jesus Campusano mural
  Artists Embassy, 1972 (3 letters): see also Master Travel Corporation; Peoples' Republic of China, Embassy of
  Artists Equity Association, 1950-1983 (11 letters): see also San Francisco Art Association
  Assadourian, Ohannes: see Fresno State College
  B., Esther and Bebe, 1950 (1 letter): mentions Katharine Kuh
  Baker, Howard H. (Senator), 1983 (1 letter)
  Baldwin/Clarke Associates, Inc., 1980 (1 letter): re Mirabeau Restaurant panels donated to the Oakland Museum
  Ball, Seymour, 1963 (1 letter)
  Bancroft, C., 1972 (1 letter)
  Barbour, Barbara Fletcher, 1975 (1 letter)
  Bay Area Rapid Transit District (BART), 1975 (2 letters)
  Bayer, Dr. Leona: see Wolff, Dr. and Mrs.
  Bazell, Arthur H. (psychiatrist), 1986 (1 letter)
  Beeson, Richard, 1983 (1 letter)
  Belew, Louise, 1973 (1 letter): re Packard family history
  Benét, Mary Liles, 1969-1973 (2 letters)
  Berkley, Randall and Harvey, 1967-1968 (3 letters)
  Bernstien, Becky and Oscar, 1969 (3 letters)
  Bethany United Methodist Church, 1985 (1 letter): re mural by Christine Puskas-Dresner for Noe Valley
  Bingaman, Jeff (Senator), 1983 (1 letter)
  Black, Anona, 1984 (1 letter)
  Black Panthers, 1968 (1 letter)
  Bliven, Bruce, 1975 (2 letters)
  Bornholdt, Tordis (Mrs. Elvind Bornholdt), undated and 1967-1985 (18 letters)
  Boschwitz, Rudy, Dec 12, 1983 (Senator), 1983 (1 letter)
  Boxer, Barbara, 1983 (1 letter)
  Brand, Marjorie, 1967 (1 letter)
  Brehm, Barbara, 1970 (1 letter)
  Brewer, Tom (American Society to Defend Children), 1966 (2 letters)
  Bridges, Nikki, 1980 (3 letters): mention actress Lee Grant's interest in filming Packard family history, and include a letter from Kazuyuki Fujii
  Brooklyn Museum, 1971 (1 letter)
  Broudy, Thalia Stern: see Stern, Thalia
  Brown Brothers Adjusters, 1975 (2 letters) see also Petersen, Lonergan and Larson
  Brown, Phoebe, 1980-1984 (5 letters)
  Bufano, Beniamino, 1957 (1 letter)
  Bull, Henrik (Bull, Field, Volkmann, Stockwell), 1971 (1 letter)
  Bunce, Eda, 1966 (1 letter)
  Caen, Herb, 1968 (1 letter): from Packard
  Cairns, Donald, Kathé, Megan, Shannon, undated and 1966-1977 (82 letters)
  California Academy of Sciences, 1965 (1 letter)
  California Living, 1981 (1 letter): including typescript "Emmy Lou Packard, The Artist in Profile" by Pat Pfeiffer: see also Pfeiffer, Pat
  California State College, Sonoma, 1977 (1 letter)
  California State Library, 1973 (2 letters)
  California State Parks and Recreation Department, 1987 (1 letter)
  California, University of, Berkeley, 1962-1984 (24 letters)
  California, University of, Berkeley, Art Museum, 1978 (1 letter)
  California, University of, San Francisco, 1973 (1 letter)
  California, University of, Santa Cruz, 1974 (2 letters)
  Calmar Press, 1963 (1 letter)
  Campusano, Jesus ("Chuy") and Dianne, 1974-1986 (2 letters)
  Cannon, Chuck, Von, Syd, Steff, Laurie, 1984 (1 letter)
  Carleton College, 1967 (2 letters)
  Carmel Art Museum, 1970 (3 letters)
  Carr, Jack Carr Gallery, 1977 (1 letter)
  Carter, Dudley: see Montoya, Emmanuel
  Carter, President Jimmy, 1977 (1 letter): from Packard
  Casady, Si, 1966 (1 letter)
  Catlett, E., 1975 (2 letters) see also Mora, E. C. ("Betty")
  Center for the Visual Arts, 1976-1979 (2 letters)
  Cerda, F., 1981 (1 letter)
  Chapman Press, 1963 (1 letter)
  Chegodaev, Andrei and Mrs., 1965 (1 letter)
  Children's Center, Inc., 1979 (1 letter)
  Chrisman, Gale Randall, 1968-1985 (5 letters)
  Chrisman, Laura, undated and 1969-1974 (7 letters)
  Chrisman, Robert (editor, The Black Scholar), 1974-1985 (5 letters)
  Cirino, Nick and Arbutus, 1966 (1 letter)
  City College of San Francisco, 1983 (1 letter)
  Clark, Anne (Mrs. Joseph H. Clark, Jr.), 1974 (1 letter)
  Clarke, John Henrik (African World Bookshelf), 1967 (1 letter)
  Cluff, Peggy, 1966 (1 letter)
  Coastal Insurance Agency, 1973 (2 letters)
  Coffield, Clara Packard, 1984-1985 (2 letters, re family history) see also Smith, Richard
  Coffield, Joel (Packard's brother-in-law), 1963 (1 letter)
  Coleman, Judy and Esmond, 1984-1985 (2 letters)
  Committee for Solidarity with the Chilean People, 1976 (1 letter)
  Coons, Ms., 1963 (1 letter)
  Cope, Dr., 1968 (1 letter)
  Corbett, Jack N., 1982 (1 letter)
  Correll, Richard V. ("Dick") and Alice, 1972-1984 (3 letters)
  Cowell, Henry and Sidney, 1959-1985 (16 letters)
  Cranston, Alan (Senator), 1983 (1 letter)
  Cravath, Ruth, 1963 (1 letter)
  E. B. Crocker Art Gallery, 1965 (1 letter)
  Crowell, Sidney, 1969 (1 letter)
  Crump, Bob, 1972 (1 letter)
  Crunewald, Mrs., 1967 (1 letter)
  Cunningham, Imogen, 1973 (1 letter)
  Curtis, Jessie A., 1965 (1 letter)
  Cushing, Lincoln, 1981 (1 letter)
  Cylich, Elida and Bernard, 1983 (1 letter)
  Danilova, Yevgenia, 1971 (2 letters)
  Darnis, Upiek and Marina, 1971-1983 (10 letters)
  Davies, Lily (Davies Book Company Limited), 1966-1968 (5 letters)
  Davis, Fania, 1979 (1 letter)
  Davis, Jane Grace, 1967-1985 (6 letters)
  Davis Publications, Inc., 1971 (4 letters)
  de Lappe, Pele, 1981-1984 (3 letters)
  Delgado, Doris, 1984-1985 (2 letters)
  deLima, Agnes, 1966 (1 letter)
  Dellums, Ronald V. (Congressman), 1983 (1 letter)
  DeMars, Vernon (architect) and Betty, 1977-1983 (3 letters)
  Depot Gallery, 1973-1975 (10 letters)
  De Velbiss, Robert, 1968 (1 letter)
  deTours Gallery, 1965 (1 letter)
  M. H. de Young Memorial Museum, 1965-1971 (2 letters)
  Dialog Magazine, 1965 (1 letter)
  Dickerson, Edward, 1964 (1 letter)
  Djamarin, Amsir, 1973 (1 letter)
  Dodd, Christopher J. (Senator), 1983 (2 letters)
  Domhoff, Lynne, 1980 (1 letter)
  Douglas, Marshall and Lori, 1966-1972 (8 letters)
  Dreyfus, Benjamin, 1982 (1 letter): see also Wolff, Dr. Ernst and Mrs. (Leona Bayer)
  Duimovich, Betty, 1973-1985 (12 letters)
  Dumhoff, Helen, 1979 (1 letter)
  Dunbar, Paul Lawrence, 1984 (1 letter)
  Dusheck, G., 1969 (1 letter)
  Duveneck, Josephine W., 1973 (1 letter)
  East, John P. (Senator), 1983 (1 letter)
  Eckbo, Garrett (Eckbo, Dean, Austin and Williams), 1965 (1 letter)
  Edmunds, John (composer) and B., 1945-1985 (33 letters)
  Edom's Interior Design, 1970 (2 letters)
  Elman, Kate, 1984 (1 letter)
  Erb, Bill, Evelyn, and Lyndall, 1980 (1 letter)
  Erb, Guy Feliz and Iva, 1981-1985 (6 letters)
  Eriksson, Adelyne and Per, 1978 (1 letter)
  Escher, Earl W. and Miriam, 1955 (1 letter)
  Eshleman, Jack, 1969 (1 letter)
  Estados Unidos Mexicanos, 1974 (1 letter)
  Etigson, Rafe, 1971 (1 letter)
  Ets-Hokins, Mr., 1965 (1 letter)
  Euphrat, Helen Euphrat Gallery, 1984 (1 letter)
  Farm Labor Organizing Committee, 1983 (1 letter)
  Ferry, W. H. (Center for the Study of Democratic Inst.), 1968 (1 letter)
  Fisher, Nancy J. (Jenner Street Gallery), 1975-1976 (6 letters)
  Fithian, Floyd (colleague of Scoop Jackson), 1983 (1 letter)
  Foley, Heather, 1969 (1 letter)
  Ford, Patricia C., 1974-1985 (4 letters)
  Forster, Paul, 1983 (1 letter)
  Frankenstein, Alfred, 1941 (1 letter)
  Freed, Jeffrey (San Francisco State College), 1967 (1 letter)
  Fresno State College, 1967 (1 letter)
  Friese, Robert Charles, 1974 (2 letters)
  Fromer, Jon, 1984 (1 letter)
  Fuapopo, Sekio ("Zeke"), 1973-1984 (4 letters)
  Fuller, Mary, 1977 (1 letter)
  Fullbright, William, 1966 (1 letter)
  Fumino, Adele, 1972-1985 (3 letters)
  Galeria de la Raza/Studio 24, 1985 (1 letter)
  Gardner ?, Maxine, 1985 (2 letters)
  Garfield, Morton M., 1966 (1 letter)
  Gaw, William A., 1955 (1 letter)
  Geoffroy, Evelyn, 1973 (1 letter)
  Gilbert, Louise, 1984 (2 letters)
  Ginzton, Edward L. (Varian Associates) and Artemas, 1972-1990 (6 letters): see also Archives of American Art; Ziegler, William
  Glenn, John (Senator), 1983 (1 letter)
  Gold, Mike and Elizabeth, 1964-1965 (3 letters)
  Gold, Sam, Mollie, undated and 1984 (2 letters)
  Goldmeer, Marilyn, 1966 (1 letter)
  Golstein, Stephen, 1974 (1 letter)
  Goode, Barry, Erica, and Adam, 1981 (1 letter)
  Goodwin, James C. and Eva, 1968-1985 (4 letters)
  Gränich, Elisabeth, 1968 (1 letter)
  Grant, Lee (actress), 1981 (1 letter)
  Grassi American Corporation, 1964 (1 letter)
  Graubard, William, 1973 (1 letter)
  Gray Panthers of San Francisco, 1985 (1 letter)
  Greene, Burton and Margot, 1984 (2 letters)
  Gross, Margo, 1972 (1 letter)
  Grossman, Hazel, 1963 (1 letter)
  Grover, Sherwood and Kate, 1984 (1 letter)
  Grunewald, Estelle, 1982 (2 letters)
  Guggenheim, John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1950 (1 letter)
  Guttmann, Ethel Weiner (Guttman and MacRitchie), 1970-1985 (4 letters)
  Hamburg, Alice (Women's International League for Peace and Freedom), 1968-1985 (2 letters)
  Hanson, Anne,1965 (1 letter)
  Happ, Mildred, 1965 (1 letter)
  Harjan, Nancy, 1966 (1 letter)
  Harris, Gertrude, 1979 (1 letter)
  Harris, Henrietta, 1984 (1 letter)
  Harris, Jerry, 1973 (1 letter)
  Hart, Gary (Senator), 1983 (1 letter)
  Hathaway, Charles ("Chuck") 1972-1973 (4 letters)
  Hathaway, Joan, 1973 (1 letter)
  Hayes, Elinor, 1982 (1 letter)
  Heartland Productions, 1983 (1 letter)
  Heathcote, Judge, 1966 (1 letter)
  Heflin, Howell (Senator), 1983 (1 letter)
  Helms, Jesse (Senator), 1983 (1 letter): form letter re Grenada
  Hendrickson, David, 1983 (1 letter)
  Herendeen, Jerry, 1968 (3 letters)
  Herndon, Richard E. (Heller, Ehrman, White and McAuliffe), 1963 (4 letters)
  Herring, Frances, 1965-1976 (5 letters)
  Hersh, George L., 1962 (1 letter)
  Hess, Rudolf, 1950 (1 letter)
  Himelhoch, Myra: see California, University of, Berkeley
  Hobbs, Frederic (San Francisco Art Center), 1963 (1 letter)
  Hollings, Ernest F. (Senator), 1983 (1 letter) Holloway, Jan, 1985 (1 letter)
  Holmes, Rosinda, 1983-1984 (2 letters)
  Horton, Ronald, 1966 (1 letter)
  Hovanec, Jeanne, 1971 (1 letter)
  Howard, Blanche and Lacey ?, 1977 (1 letter)
  Hudson, Lois, 1965-1967 (3 letters)
  Huerta, Dolores: see also United Farm Workers
  Hughes, Edan M., 1983 (1 letter)
  Ingalabe, Gene (managing editor, Farmland), 1967 (1 letter)
  Institute of International Education (Alice A. Adanalian), 1950 (2 letters)
  International Art Manifesto for the Legal Defense of Political Prisoners, 1973 (1 letter)
  International Institute for Peace, 1965 (1 letter)
  International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union, 1954-1985 (5 letters)
  Irish, Hal, 1973 (1 letter)
  Irvine, Charles L. ("Tad") and Charlotte, 1972-1983 (5 letters)
  Jackman, Mary and Norman, 1965-1968 (2 letters)
  Jackson, Jesse, 1984 (1 letter) Jacob, Dorothy, 1970 (2 letters)
  Jänecke + Schneemann, 1971 (1 letter)
  Jenkins, David (David Jenkins and Associates), 1975 (1 letter)
  Jenner Street Gallery: see Fisher, Nancy J.
  Jewett, Bethany and Masha [Zakheim?], 1984 (1 letter)
  Johnson, Arline (Mrs. Jack A. Johnson), 1972 (1 letter)
  Johnson, Jean, 1966 (1 letter)
  Johnson, Karolyne Marie, 1984 (1 letter)
  Johnson, Lyndon B., 1964-1967 (2 letters)
  Jones, Mary Ellen: see California, University of, Berkeley
  Joseph, Emily (Mrs. Sidney Joseph), 1941 (1 letter)
  Joslin Diabetes Foundation, Inc., 1978 (1 letter)
  Joyce, Robert, 1970 (1 letter)
  Kaiper, Bruce, 1983 (1 letter)
  Kasten, Robert W. (Senator), 1983 (1 letter)
  Kaufman, Herbert C., 1985 (1 letter)
  Kavin, Eda, 1980-1984 (2 letters) Kennedy, Alice and Roy, 1980 (2 letters)
  Kenney, Jerry, 1982 (1 letter)
  Keys, Lavinia, 1968 (1 letter)
  Kibbee, Wallace, 1963 (1 letter)
  King, Hayward, 1984 (1 letter)
  Kirshner, Michael, 1977 (1 letter)
  Kitanishi, Makoto, 1966-1969 (3 letters)
  Klimoff, N., 1965 (1 letter)
  Knapp, Susan, 1983 (1 letter)
  Kogan, Julius, 1974 (1 letter)
  Kohlman, Alan, 1970 (1 letter)
  Kolmar Associates, 1980 (1 letter)
  Koppel, Stanley and Virginia, 1976 (1 letter)
  Korean National Peace Committee, 1965 (1 letter)
  Kossow, Richard E., 1972 (1 letter): see also Hathaway, Charles
  KQED-Channel 9, 1976 (1 letter)
  KRON-Channel 4, 1978 (1 letter)
  Kronfeld, Marion, 1983 (1 letter)
  Kurdina, Vera, undated and 1964-1983 (13 letters)
  Lafe, Steve, 1978 (1 letter)
  Lane Publishing, 1965 (1 letter)
  Lange, Dorothea, undated and 1962 (2 letters)
  Langhorst, Frederick L. (AIA), 1971 (1 letter)
  Laughlin, Sharon, 1980-1982 (3 letters)
  Laxalt, Paul (Senator), 1983 (1 letter)
  Leahy, Dan, 1980 (1 letter)
  Lee, Russel Van Arsdale, 1973-1979 (2 letters)
  Leff, David N. and Alena, 1965-1972 (4 letters)
  Leff, Jordan, 1968 (1 letter)
  Lenoir, Henri, 1984 (1 letter)
  Letelier, Orlando: see Committee for Solidarity with the Chilean People; United States Department of State
  Levy, Eveni, 1973 (1 letter)
  Library of Congress, 1971 (1 letter)
  Liles, Robert (Good Housekeeping), 1968 (1 letter)
  Lilienthal, Philip and Sally, 1977 (1 letter)
  Lilli Ann Corporation, 1985 (1 letter)
  Lima, Helen and Albert J. "Mickie," 1981 (1 letter)
  Lindgren, Frank T. and Helen, 1961-1966 (2 letters)
  Lombardi, Frank, 1951 (1 letter)
  Lubin, Jerry, 1974 (1 letter)
  Lucy, Esther (Mrs. F. Allen Lucy), 1974-1982 (2 letters)
  Lugar, Richard G. (Senator), 1983 (1 letter)
  Mackey, Bugie, 1965-1974 (6 letters)
  Mallory, Clyde, undated (1 letter)
  Mandel, William M. and Tanya, 1966-1980 (2 letters): see Chrisman, Robert
  Markels, Bobby, 1966 (1 letter)
  Martens, Wilma M. (Veterans Administration), 1963 (1 letter)
  Master Travel Corporation, 1972 (1 letter)
  Mathias, Charles McC. (Senator), 1983 (1 letter)
  Maxwell Galleries, Ltd., 1971 (1 letter) see Misrachi, Alberto